[
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>scip</em>) #### sceal genægled⁠ — The ship must be nailed",
        "correctAnswer": "scip",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges (<em>word</em>) #### is soþ⁠ — The king's word is truth",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation":"Here 'word' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Godes (<em>bearn</em>) #### þrowode on þære rood⁠ — God's son suffered on the cross",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>wif</em>) #### wæs gehæled of ðam wite⁠ — The woman was healed of the disease",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hiora (<em>god</em>) #### syndon drycræfta lareowas⁠ — Their gods are teachers of magical arts",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is the subject and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "god",
                "explanation": "Here 'god' is the subject and plural, but since 'god' has a short syllable it should take a 'u' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>scip</em>) #### Norðmanna cam on þissum dæg⁠ — The Northmen's ships came on this day",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is the subject and plural, so since 'scip' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif þa (<em>word</em>) #### sind soþ⁠ — If the words are true",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation":"Here 'word' is the subject and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Geata (<em>bearn</em>) #### ferde to him⁠ — The children of the Geats went to him ",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is the subject and plural, so since 'bearn' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo geofu wæs broht for ðære synne ðæs ærestan (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — The grace was brought for the sin of the first woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wifes",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs hiora (<em>god</em>) #### preost⁠ — He was the priest of their god",
        "correctAnswer": "godes",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæs (<em>scip</em>) #### mæst geburnen⁠ — The ship's mast burned",
        "correctAnswer": "scipes",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt þurh (<em>bearn</em>) #### gebyrd butan weres frigum, byrd eacen wearð⁠ — Through the bearing of a child without a man's embrace, that bride became great",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnes",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo is sæd ærest (<em>wif</em>) #### in Norþanhymbra mægþe ðæt heo munuchade onfenge⁠ — She is said to have been one of the first women in Northumbria to have taken nun-hood",
        "correctAnswer": "wifa",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "wif",
                "explanation":"Here 'wif' is in the genitive plural as she is 'one of the first', so it takes the 'a' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis dæg, com þæs hæthenes (<em>god</em>) #### wigan⁠ — On that day, the warriors of the heathen gods came",
        "correctAnswer": "goda",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "godes",
                "explanation":"Here 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending, not the singular 'es' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða het se cyning (<em>scip</em>) #### gegearcian⁠ — Then the king ordered the preparation of ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipa",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlosna to þæs Godes (<em>word</em>) ####⁠ — Listen to the word of God",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation":"Here 'word' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He Noe gebletsade and his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He blessed Noah and his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He spræc to þæt (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — He spoke to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða godu fram Egiptum landum beoþ fremede (<em>god</em>) #### ⁠ — The gods from Egypt are strange gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wolde geseean helle (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — he would visit the gods of hell",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt wæron þa erestan (<em>scip</em>) #### Deniscra manna the Angelcynnes land geseah⁠ — Those were the first ships of Danish men the English people's land saw",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie writon micel (<em>word</em>) #### lofa⁠ — They wrote many words of praise",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation":"Here 'word' is the direct object and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se fæder wið-soc eall to his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — The father denied all to his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearne",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "bearn",
                "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending. It is 'eall' which is the direct object"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "And mon mot feohtan orwige gif he gemeteþ oðerne æt his æwum (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — And a man can fight without charge of homicide if he finds another with his lawful wife",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo cwen geaf þa boc to þæm ####⁠ — The queen gave the book to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We willaþ mid þam sceattum us to þæm (<em>scip</em>) #### gangan⁠ — We wish to go to the ship with the treasure",
        "correctAnswer": "scipe",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ærist scoop eorþan for his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He first shaped the earth for his children",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnum",
        "explanation":"Here 'bearn' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo geaf micel giefa to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — She gave many gifts to the women",
        "correctAnswer": "wifum",
        "explanation":"Here 'wif' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie bædon to hiora (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — They prayed to their gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godum",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se here ferde to þæm (<em>scip</em>) ####⁠ — The army went to the ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipum",
        "explanation":"Here 'scip' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]
